JavaScript is the language that makes websites interactive.
JavaScript 是使网站互动的语言
If you've ever been on a website that automatically updates content,
如果你曾访问过自动更新内容的网站
JavaScript was doing that.
那就是 JavaScript 做的
Anything like a fade-in or a popup,
任何像淡入或弹出的东西
those are done with JavaScript.
都是用 JavaScript 完成的
To build the data dashboard,
要构建数据仪表板
you won't need to actually write any JavaScript,
你不需要实际编写任何 JavaScript
but both the Bootstrap library that you'll use for CSS and
但是你将用于 CSS 的 Bootstrap 库
the Plotly library that you'll use for making charts used JavaScript.
以及将用于图表的 Plotly 库都是使用 JavaScript 编写的
So, this will give you an idea of how these libraries actually work.
因此 JavaScript 将使你理解这些库的实际工作方式
Here's a basic toy example of JavaScript.
这里是一个简单的基础 JavaScript 示例
In lines eight through 12 of the code,
在第 8 到第 12 行的代码中
I've written a function that changes the header text when I click on the image.
我写了一个函数 当点击图像时会更改标题文本
Let's see how it works.
让我们看看它是如何工作的
So, I go onto the page,
进入页面
I click the image,
点击图片
and you'll notice up here that the h1 tag text changed.
你会注意到这里的 h1 标签文本发生了变化
Here are a few things of note about this code.
以下是有关此代码的一些注意事项
First, the JavaScript code goes between script's tags.
首先 JavaScript 代码位于 script 标签之间
Notice as well that I added an on-click attribute
另外请注意 我在图像标签添加了
to the image tag and specified the function in.
一个 onclick 属性 并指定了其中的函数
That's down here in line 28.
就在 28 行这里
Also, the JavaScript syntax to me at least is a bit funny looking.
对我来说 JavaScript 语法看起来有点奇怪
JavaScript has a relatively complex syntax when it comes to making websites interactive.
在使网站互动时 JavaScript 的语法相对复杂
In this case, I'm saying,
在这个示例中 代码中的意思是
look at the HTML document,
看看 HTML 文档
get all the h1 elements,
获取所有的 h1 元素
give me the first h1 tag,
给我第一个 h1 标签
and then change it to HTML.
然后修改它的 html
The actual on-click functionality happens because like I showed before,
函数在点击时发生是因为 就像我之前展示的
I put in on-click attribute in the image tag.
我在图像标签中添加了 onclick 属性
Thankfully, there are libraries that make
值得庆幸的是 有些库可以
working with JavaScript and front end development easier.
使 JavaScript 和前端开发变得更容易
Here, I'll show you one library called jQuery that makes JavaScript much easier to use.
这里展示一个名为 jQuery 的库 它使 JavaScript 更易于使用
First, you'll need to link to the jQuery library either by
首先需要链接到 jQuery 库
downloading the file or pointing to a web address containing the library.
不论是指向已下载文件或指向包含库的 Web 地址
You can download the jQuery file from
你可以从 jQuery 网站下载 jQuery 文件
the jQuery website or you can use a link that contains the file.
或者也可以使用包含该文件的链接
For example, Google has the jQuery library
比如谷歌就有可以链接的
on the web that you can link to. I'm going to do that.
jQuery 我打算使用这个
So, I'm going to erase the JavaScript code that I've already
我要删除已经编写的 JavaScript 代码
written and I'm going to link to the jQuery library.
链接到 jQuery 库
Now, I'm going to make a new script's tag and a closing tag,
现在 我要制作一个新的 script 标签及其结束标签
and then write some jQuery code here in between.
然后在这里写一些 jQuery 代码
This is saying, wait for the document to get ready.
代码的意思是 当 html 文档准备好
In other words, waiting for the document to load,
换句话说 等待文档加载
then grab the image tag,
然后抓取图像标签
put on on-click function,
放上 click 函数
and finally, change the h1 tag text.
最后修改 h1 标签文本
Then, I just need to close all of my brackets in parentheses and you can see it works.
然后我只需要关闭所有的括号 你就可以看到该功能的实现
When I click on the image,
点击图片时
the h1 tag changes.
h1 标签发生了变化
Also, just like CSS,
另外 就像 CSS 一样
I can either include the code in the HTML file using a script's tag or alternatively,
我可以使用 script 标签在 HTML 文件中包含代码 或者
I can put the JavaScript into a separate file and link to that file.
也可以将 JavaScript 放入单独的文件并链接到该文件
I'm going to do that now. So, I'm going to just create a new file,
我现在打算这样做 所以要创建一个新文件
let's call it interaction.js where JS is for JavaScript.
称之为 interaction.js 其中 js 是指 JavaScript
Now, I'm going to cut this JavaScript code and put it into my interaction.js file.
现在我将剪切这段 JavaScript 代码并将其放入 interaction.js 文件中
Then, here, in the script's tag,
然后在这里 在 script 标签中
I need to specify the source,
我需要指定来源
which in this case is just this interaction.js file,
在这个例子中 只有 interaction.js 文件
which is in the same folder as the HTML document,
它与 HTML 文档位于同一文件夹中
and notice that the jQuery code still works.
注意 jQuery 代码仍然有效
So, that's essentially JavaScript and what you can do with JavaScript.
这就是基础的 JavaScript 以及使用 JavaScript 可以做些什么
Before you move on to the JavaScript exercises,
在继续 JavaScript 练习之前
I just want to give you two more examples of some jQuery code.
我想再展示一些 jQuery 代码的例子
So currently, this document has the same code as before where if you click on the image,
目前这个文档与以前的代码相同 如果你点击图像
the text in the h1 tag will change.
h1 标签中的文字将会改变
Okay. So, what else can we add?
那么 我们还能添加什么?
jQuery gives you a lot of options.
jQuery 为你提供了很多选择
So, I'm going to add two things.
我要添加两个效果
One, I'm going to add a fade in when the page loads and just as another example,
第一 在页面加载时添加淡入淡出 另一个示例
I'm going to have the image fade out when I click on the h1 tag at the top.
当点击顶部的 h1 标签时 使图像淡出
So, let me code that for you.
让我来编写代码
So, like before, you have to get the document and wait for it to be ready.
像之前一样 你必须获取文档并等待它准备好
Now, I want to add something to the body tag.
现在 我想在 body 标签上添加一些东西
So, I have to select the body tag.
所以我必须选择 body 标签
Now, I'm going to say,
现在我要
hide the body tag.
隐藏 body 标签
So, it's going to hide all of the content on load and then I want to fade in slowly.
所以 它会在加载时隐藏所有内容 然后我想慢慢淡入
Notice as well, here, I've used double quotes.
请注意 在这里我使用了双引号
Here, I've used single quotes.
在这里 我使用了单引号
It actually doesn't matter,
实际上没关系
but I should be consistent about it and either do double quotes or single quotes.
不过我应该保持一致 都用双引号或都用单引号
Now, I'm just going to close all of our brackets in parentheses.
现在 我将关闭所有括号
You notice now when the page loads,
现在可以注意到页面加载时
it has a slow fade in.
它的淡入淡出
Okay. Now, let's add the extra click functionality where
好的 现在添加额外的点击功能
clicking on the h1 title at the top will fade out the image at the bottom.
单击顶部的 h1 标题将淡出底部的图像
So again, you wait for the document to load and be ready.
再次等待文档加载并准备好
Now, we want to add a click function to the h1 tag,
现在我们要在 h1 标签中添加一个 click 函数
and then we want to take the image,
然后我们想获取图像
and fade it out slowly,
将其慢慢淡出
and then we close all our brackets again,
然后我们再次关闭所有括号
and see if it worked.
看看它是否有效
There it goes. So, the jQuery documentation is pretty extensive and again,
确实淡出了 所以 jQuery 文档是非常广泛的
the libraries we're going to use are actually going to take care of the jQuery for you,
我们将要使用的库实际上也将为你处理 jQuery
but I at least wanted you to understand what was going on underneath the hood.
但我希望你至少了解底层发生的事情
So, use the information in this video to help you
使用此视频中的信息帮助你完成
out with the jQuery exercise coming up next.
随后出现的 jQuery 练习